A randomized, controlled, double-blind study of <intervention>light emitting diode photomodulation</intervention> for the prevention of <condition>radiation dermatitis</condition> in patients with breast cancer. Radiation dermatitis occurs in a majority of patients with breast cancer who receive radiation therapy (RT), causes significant pain, and may necessitate treatment delay. Light emitting diode (LED) photomodulation has been reported to minimize radiation dermatitis. This study sought to further evaluate the efficacy of LED photomodulation in lessening radiation dermatitis. After surgery, patients with breast cancer received LED photomodulation or <control>sham treatments</control> in conjunction with three-dimensional conformal RT. Reactions were evaluated using standardized photographs graded according to National Cancer Institute criteria. In the LED treatment group (n=<No-of-participants>18</No-of-participants>), <intervention-value>no</intervention-value> patients had <outcome>grade 0 reactions</outcome>, <intervention-value>six</intervention-value> (<intervention-value>33.3%</intervention-value>) had <outcome>grade 1 reactions</outcome>, <intervention-value>12</intervention-value> (<intervention-value>66.7%</intervention-value>) had <outcome>grade 2 reactions</outcome>, and <intervention-value>none</intervention-value> had a <outcome>grade 3 reaction</outcome>. In the sham treatment group (n=<control-participants>15</control-participants>), <control-value>one</control-value> (<control-value>6.6%</control-value>) patient had a <outcome>grade 0 reaction</outcome>, <control-value>four</control-value> (<control-value>26.7%</control-value>) had <outcome>grade 1 reactions</outcome>, <control-value>9</control-value> (<control-value>60.0%</control-value>) had <outcome>grade 2 reactions</outcome>, and <control-value>one</control-value> (<control-value>6.7%</control-value>) had a <outcome>grade 3 reaction</outcome>. <intervention-value>Two</intervention-value> (<intervention-value>11.1%</intervention-value>) patients in the LED treatment group and <control-value>one</control-value> (<control-value>6.7%)</control-value> in the control group had to <outcome>interrupt treatment</outcome>. Differences between groups were not statistically significant. LED photomodulation did not reduce the incidence of radiation-induced skin reactions or interruptions in therapy. .  