<intervention>Weight lifting</intervention> for women at risk for breast cancer-related <condition>lymphedema</condition>: a randomized trial. Clinical guidelines for breast cancer survivors without lymphedema advise against upper body exercise, preventing them from obtaining established health benefits of weight lifting. To evaluate lymphedema onset after a 1-year weight lifting intervention vs <control>no exercise (control)</control> among survivors at risk for breast cancer-related lymphedema (BCRL). A randomized controlled equivalence trial (Physical Activity and Lymphedema trial) in the <location>Philadelphia</location> metropolitan area of <No-of-participants>154</No-of-participants> <eligibility>breast cancer survivors 1 to 5 years postunilateral breast cancer, with at least 2 lymph nodes removed and without clinical signs of BCRL at study entry</eligibility>. Participants were recruited <duration>between October 1, 2005, and February 2007</duration>, with data collection ending in August 2008. Weight lifting intervention included a gym membership and 13 weeks of supervised instruction, with the remaining 9 months unsupervised, vs no exercise. <outcome-Measure>Incident BCRL</outcome-Measure> determined by increased arm swelling during 12 months (≥5% increase in interlimb difference). <outcome-Measure>Clinician-defined BCRL onset</outcome-Measure> was also evaluated. Equivalence margin was defined as doubling of lymphedema incidence. A total of <No-of-participants>134</No-of-participants> participants completed follow-up measures at 1 year. The proportion of women who experienced <outcome>incident BCRL onset</outcome> was <intervention-value>11%</intervention-value> (<intervention-value>8</intervention-value> of <intervention-participants>72</intervention-participants>) in the weight lifting intervention group and <control-value>17%</control-value> (<control-value>13</control-value> of <control-participants>75</control-participants>) in the control group (cumulative incidence difference [CID], -6.0%; 95% confidence interval [CI], -17.2% to 5.2%; P for equivalence = .04). Among women with 5 or more lymph nodes removed, the proportion who experienced <outcome>incident BCRL onset</outcome> was <intervention-value>7%</intervention-value> (<intervention-value>3</intervention-value> of <intervention-participants>45</intervention-participants>) in the weight lifting intervention group and <control-value>22%</control-value> (<control-value>11</control-value> of <control-participants>49</control-participants>) in the control group (CID, -15.0%; 95% CI, -18.6% to -11.4%; P for equivalence = .003). <outcome>Clinician-defined BCRL onset</outcome> occurred in <intervention-value>1</intervention-value> woman in the weight lifting intervention group and <control-value>3</control-value> women in the control group (<intervention-value>1.5%</intervention-value> vs <control-value>4.4%</control-value>, P for equivalence = .12). In breast cancer survivors at risk for lymphedema, a program of slowly progressive weight lifting compared with no exercise did not result in increased incidence of lymphedema. clinicaltrials.gov Identifier: NCT00194363. 