The effect of <intervention>transdermal estradiol</intervention> or <intervention>oral conjugated oestrogen</intervention> and <intervention>fenretinide</intervention> versus <control>placebo</control> on <condition>haemostasis and cardiovascular risk</condition> biomarkers in a randomized breast cancer chemoprevention trial. We have previously reported the favourable effect of transdermal estradiol (E2), relative to oral conjugated equine oestrogen (CEE), on ultrasensitive C-reactive protein after 12 months of treatment in a retinoid-placebo controlled two-by-two randomized breast cancer prevention trial (Decensi A et al (2002) Circulation106 10 1224-8). Here, we investigate the <outcome-Measure>changes in lipids</outcome-Measure> and <outcome-Measure>clotting profile</outcome-Measure> in patients of the same trial. Recent <eligibility>post-menopausal women</eligibility> were randomised to either oral CEE 0.625 mg/day and placebo (n = <control-participants>55</control-participants>), CEE and fenretinide 200 mg/day (n = <intervention-participants>56</intervention-participants>), transdermal E2 50 mg/day and placebo (n = <control-participants>59</control-participants>) or E2 and fenretinide 200 mg/day (n = <intervention-participants>56</intervention-participants>). Sequential medroxyprogesterone acetate 10 mg/day was given in each group. After <duration>12 months</duration>, there was a statistically significant effect of the route of administration of hormone replacement therapy (HRT) on <outcome>fibrinogen levels</outcome>; the median percentage change being <intervention-value>-5.7%</intervention-value> with CEE and <intervention-value>-1.1%</intervention-value> with E2 (p = 0.012). <outcome>Total cholesterol</outcome> decreased in all arms (p &lt; 0.0001). <outcome>HDL-C</outcome> decreased significantly with transdermal E2 (p = 0.006) compared to oral CEE and with fenretinide relative to placebo (p&lt;.001). <outcome>Triglycerides</outcome> exhibited an opposite modulation in the HRT route, with a <intervention-value>21.4%</intervention-value> median increase with oral CEE and an <intervention-value>8.6%</intervention-value> reduction with transdermal E2 (p &lt; 0.0001). <outcome>Antithrombin-III</outcome> showed a <intervention-value>4%</intervention-value> borderline significant reduction in the fenretinide arm relative to placebo, irrespective of the HRT administration route (p = 0.055). Our data indicate that transdermal E2 may be preferable to oral CEE based on its safer cardiovascular risk profile. Fenretinide modified some cardiovascular risk biomarkers and confirmed a safer profile compared to other retinoids. 