Effects of <intervention>exercise</intervention> during adjuvant chemotherapy on breast cancer outcomes. Observational studies suggest that physical activity after a breast cancer diagnosis is associated with improved cancer outcomes; however, no randomized data are available. Here, we report an exploratory follow-up of cancer outcomes from the Supervised Trial of Aerobic versus Resistance Training (START). The START was a <location>Canadian</location> multicenter trial that randomized <No-of-participants>242</No-of-participants> breast cancer patients <duration>between 2003 and 2005</duration> to <control>usual care</control> (n = <control-participants>82</control-participants>), supervised aerobic (n = <intervention-participants>78</intervention-participants>), or resistance (n = <intervention-participants>82</intervention-participants>) exercise during chemotherapy. The primary end point for this exploratory analysis was <outcome-Measure>disease-free survival (DFS)</outcome-Measure>. Secondary end points were <outcome-Measure>overall survival</outcome-Measure>, <outcome-Measure>distant DFS</outcome-Measure>, and <outcome-Measure>recurrence-free interval</outcome-Measure>. The two exercise arms were combined for analysis (n = <intervention-participants>160</intervention-participants>), and selected subgroups were explored. After a median follow-up of 89 months, there were <intervention-value>25</intervention-value>/<intervention-participants>160</intervention-participants> (<intervention-value>15.6%</intervention-value>) <outcome>DFS events</outcome> in the exercise groups and <control-value>18</control-value>/<control-participants>82</control-participants> (<control-value>22.0%</control-value>) in the control group. <outcome>Eight-year DFS</outcome> was <intervention-value>82.7%</intervention-value> for the exercise groups compared with <control-value>75.6%</control-value> for the control group (HR, 0.68; 95% confidence interval (CI), 0.37-1.24; log-rank, P = 0.21). Slightly stronger effects were observed for <outcome>overall survival</outcome> (HR, 0.60; 95% CI, 0.27-1.33; log-rank, P = 0.21), <outcome>distant DFS</outcome> (HR, 0.62; 95% CI, 0.32-1.19; log-rank, P = 0.15), and <outcome>recurrence-free interval</outcome> (HR, 0.58; 95% CI, 0.30-1.11; Gray test, P = 0.095). Subgroup analyses suggested potentially stronger exercise effects on <outcome>DFS for women who were overweight/obese</outcome> (HR, 0.59; 95% CI, 0.27-1.27), had <outcome>stage II/III cancer</outcome> (HR, 0.61; 95% CI, 0.31-1.20), <outcome>estrogen receptor-positive tumors</outcome> (HR, 0.58; 95% CI, 0.26-1.29), <outcome>human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-positive tumors</outcome> (HR, 0.21; 95% CI, 0.04-1.02), r<outcome>eceived taxane-based chemotherapies</outcome> (HR, 0.46; 95% CI, 0.19-1.15), and ≥85% of their <outcome>planned chemotherapy</outcome> (HR, 0.50; 95% CI, 0.25-1.01). This exploratory follow-up of the START provides the first randomized data to suggest that adding exercise to standard chemotherapy may improve breast cancer outcomes. A definitive phase III trial is warranted. 