Prevention of <condition>palmar-plantar erythrodysesthesia</condition> with an <intervention>antiperspirant</intervention> in <eligibility>breast cancer patients treated with pegylated liposomal doxorubicin</eligibility> (SAKK 92/08). Elevated concentrations of doxorubicin are found in eccrine sweat glands of the palms and soles. We therefore evaluated an antiperspirant as preventive treatment for palmar-plantar erythrodysesthesia (hand-foot syndrome) in patients with metastatic breast cancer treated with pegylated liposomal doxorubicin. An antiperspirant containing aluminum chlorohydrate or <control>placebo cream</control> was applied to the left or right hand and foot in a double-blinded manner (intra-patient randomization). The primary endpoint was the <outcome-Measure>rate of grade 2 or 3 palmar-plantar erythrodysesthesia</outcome-Measure>. A secondary endpoint was the <outcome-Measure>patient-reported symptom burden (tingling, numbness, pain, or skin problems)</outcome-Measure>. Using McNemar's matched pairs design, <No-of-participants>53</No-of-participants> patients were needed to detect a 20% difference between the treatment and placebo sides with a significance level of 5% and power of 90%. <outcome>Grade 2 or 3 PPE</outcome> occurred in 30 (58%) of <No-of-participants>52</No-of-participants> evaluable patients; in <control-value>six</control-value> patients <outcome>adverse effects</outcome> occurred on the placebo side but not on the treatment side, whereas <intervention-value>one</intervention-value> patient developed <outcome>palmar-plantar erythrodysesthesia</outcome> on the treatment side only (P = 0.07). <intervention-value>Four</intervention-value> patients developed <outcome>grade 2 or 3 palmar-plantar erythrodysesthesia on their foot</outcome> on the placebo side but not on the treatment side (P = 0.05). In the cohort with grade 2 or 3 palmar-plantar erythrodysesthesia there was a trend towards fewer dermatologic symptomatologies with the active treatment (P = 0.05), and no difference for other adverse events. Using topical aluminum chlorohydrate as an antiperspirant appears to reduce the incidence of grade 2 or 3 palmar-plantar erythrodysesthesia following pegylated liposomal doxorubicin chemotherapy for metastatic breast cancer.  