<duration>5-year</duration> follow-up of a randomized controlled trial of immediate versus delayed <intervention>zoledronic acid</intervention> for the prevention of <condition>bone loss</condition> in <eligibility>postmenopausal women with breast cancer starting letrozole after tamoxifen</eligibility>: N03CC (Alliance) trial. Postmenopausal women with breast cancer receiving aromatase inhibitors are at an increased risk of bone loss. The current study was undertaken to determine whether upfront versus delayed treatment with zoledronic acid (ZA) impacted bone loss. This report described the 5-year follow-up results. A total of <No-of-participants>551</No-of-participants> <eligibility>postmenopausal women with breast cancer who completed tamoxifen treatment and were undergoing daily letrozole treatment</eligibility> were randomized to either upfront (<intervention-participants>274</intervention-participants> patients) or <control>delayed</control> (<control-participants>277</control-participants> patients) ZA at a dose of 4 mg intravenously every 6 months. In the patients on the delayed treatment arm, ZA was initiated for a postbaseline bone mineral density T-score of <-2.0 or fracture. The incidence of a 5% <outcome>decrease in the total lumbar spine bone mineral density at 5 years</outcome> was <intervention-value>10.2%</intervention-value> in the upfront treatment arm versus <control-value>41.2%</control-value> in the delayed treatment arm (P<&lt;.0001). A total of 41 patients in the delayed treatment arm were eventually started on ZA. With the exception of increased NCI Common Toxicity Criteria (CTC) <outcome>grade 1/2 elevated creatinine and fever</outcome> in the patients treated on the upfront arm and cerebrovascular ischemia among those in the delayed treatment arm, there were no significant differences observed between arms with respect to the most common adverse events of arthralgia and back pain. <outcome>Osteoporosis</outcome> occurred less frequently in the upfront treatment arm (<intervention-value>2</intervention-value> vs <control-value>8</control-value> cumulative cases), although this difference was not found to be statistically significant. <outcome>Bone fractures</outcome> occurred in <intervention-value>24</intervention-value> patients in the upfront treatment arm versus <control-value>25</control-value> patients in the delayed treatment arm. Immediate treatment with ZA prevented bone loss compared with delayed treatment in postmenopausal women receiving letrozole and these differences were maintained at 5 years. The incidence of osteoporosis or fractures was not found to be significantly different between treatment arms.  