Sensitivity and specificity of mammography and <intervention>adjunctive ultrasonography</intervention> to screen for breast cancer in the <location>Japan</location> Strategic Anti-cancer Randomized Trial (J-START): a randomised controlled trial. Mammography is the only proven method for breast cancer screening that reduces mortality, although it is inaccurate in young women or women with dense breasts. We investigated the efficacy of adjunctive ultrasonography. <duration>Between July, 2007, and March, 2011</duration>, we enrolled asymptomatic women aged <average-age>40-49 years</average-age> at 42 study sites in 23 prefectures into the Japan Strategic Anti-cancer Randomized Trial (J-START). Eligible women had <eligibility>no history of any cancer in the previous 5 years and were expected to live for more than 5 years</eligibility>. Randomisation was done centrally by the Japan Clinical Research Support Unit. Participants were randomly assigned in 1:1 ratio to undergo mammography and ultrasonography (intervention group) or <control>mammography alone (control group)</control> twice in <duration>2 years</duration>. The primary outcome was <outcome-Measure>sensitivity</outcome-Measure>, <outcome-Measure>specificity</outcome-Measure>, <outcome-Measure>cancer detection rate</outcome-Measure>, and <outcome-Measure>stage distribution</outcome-Measure> at the first round of screening. Analysis was by intention to treat. This study is registered, number UMIN000000757. Of <No-of-participants>72,998</No-of-participants> women enrolled, <intervention-participants>36,859</intervention-participants> were assigned to the intervention group and <control-participants>36,139</control-participants> to the control group. <outcome>Sensitivity</outcome> was significantly higher in the intervention group than in the control group (<intervention-value>91·1%</intervention-value>, 95% CI 87·2-95·0 vs <control-value>77·0%</control-value>, 70·3-83·7; p=0·0004), whereas <outcome>specificity</outcome> was significantly lower (<intervention-value>87·7%</intervention-value>, 87·3-88·0 vs <control-value>91·4%</control-value>, 91·1-91·7; p&lt;·0001). More <outcome>cancers</outcome> were detected in the intervention group than in the control group (<intervention-value>184</intervention-value> [<intervention-value>0·50%]</intervention-value> vs <control-value>117</control-value> [<control-value>0·32%</control-value>], p=0·0003) and were more frequently <outcome>stage 0 and I</outcome> (<intervention-value>144</intervention-value> [<intervention-value>71·3%</intervention-value>] vs <control-value>79</control-value> [<control-value>52·0%</control-value>], p=0·0194). <intervention-value>18</intervention-value> (<intervention-value>0·05%</intervention-value>) <outcome>interval cancers</outcome> were detected in the intervention group compared with <control-value>35</control-value> (<control-value>0·10%</control-value>) in the control group (p=0·034). Adjunctive ultrasonography increases sensitivity and detection rate of early cancers. Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare of Japan.  