A pilot randomized trial to prevent <condition>sexual dysfunction</condition> in <eligibility>postmenopausal breast cancer survivors starting adjuvant aromatase inhibitor therapy</eligibility>. A randomized pilot trial evaluated the hypothesis that early intervention lessens sexual dysfunction in the first year on aromatase inhibitors. A secondary aim was comparing the efficacy of two vaginal moisturizers. <No-of-participants>Fifty-seven</No-of-participants> <eligibility>postmenopausal women with early stage breast cancer starting aromatase inhibitors</eligibility> were randomized to three treatment groups. All received a handout on managing sexual and other side effects. The <control>Usual Care group</control> received no additional therapy. The Active Treatment groups received a 6-month supply of a <intervention>vaginal moisturizer</intervention> (hyaluronic acid-based in Active Group-H and prebiotic in Active Group-P) and a <intervention>vaginal lubricant</intervention> and <intervention>dilator</intervention>, plus access to an <intervention>educational website and phone coaching</intervention>. Questionnaires completed at baseline, 6, and 12 months included the <outcome-Measure>Female Sexual Function Index (FSFI)</outcome-Measure>, <outcome-Measure>Menopausal Sexual Interest Questionnaire (MSIQ)</outcome-Measure>, <outcome-Measure>Female Sexual Distress Scale-Revised (FSDS-R)</outcome-Measure>, and a <outcome-Measure>menopausal symptom scale</outcome-Measure>. <No-of-participants>Forty-nine</No-of-participants> women (86%) provided follow-up data. <average-age>Mean age was 59</average-age> and 77% were <ethinicity>non-Hispanic Caucasian</ethinicity>. <outcome>Sexual function</outcome> was impaired at baseline, but remained stable over 12 months for all groups. The combined active treatment group had <outcome>less dyspareunia</outcome> (P = 0.07) and <outcome>sexual distress</outcome> (P = 0.02) at 6 months than the Usual Care group. At 6 months, the Active-H group improved significantly more than the Active-P group on <outcome>FSFI total score</outcome> (P = 0.04). Sexual counseling helped women maintain <outcome>stable sexual function</outcome> on aromatase inhibitors. Active intervention resulted in better outcomes at 6 months. This promising pilot trial suggests a need for more research on preventive counseling to maintain sexual function during aromatase inhibitor treatment. 