<intervention>Physical Activity</intervention> With and Without Arm Sleeves: Compliance and Quality of Life After Breast Cancer Surgery-A Randomized Controlled Trial. After breast cancer surgery patients are at higher risk of lymphedema development and decreasing physical activity (PA), as well as decreasing health-related quality of life (HRQOL). The aim of the study was to compare the level of PA and HRQOL in women after breast cancer surgery using light arm compression with women not using compression 1 year after oncological treatment. <No-of-participants>Forty-five</No-of-participants> women were preoperatively randomly assigned to a compression group (CG, n = <intervention-participants>23</intervention-participants>) or to <control>no compression group</control> (NCG, n = <control-participants>22</control-participants>). <No-of-participants>Arm volumes</No-of-participants> were measured before surgery and 12 months thereafter. The CG received circular-knit sleeves in compression class 1 for daily wearing in the postoperative period up to 1 year. Both groups underwent a standardized physical exercise program. <outcome-Measure>PA with the short version of International Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ)</outcome-Measure>, <outcome-Measure>compliance,</outcome-Measure> and <outcome-Measure>HRQOL by EORTC QLQ-C30</outcome-Measure> and <outcome-Measure>QLQ-BR23 questionnaires</outcome-Measure> was assessed in both groups 1 year after surgery. After 1 year observation the CG showed significantly lower mean affected <outcome>arm volume</outcome> compared to NCG. The <outcome>total PA</outcome> (calculated as the sum of vigorous moderate exercises and walking) was markedly higher within the CG, with no difference in particular IPAQ items. There were <outcome>no correlations between reported PA items and observed arm/edema volume or body mass index changes</outcome>. The <outcome>QLQ-BR23 revealed only better sexual functioning</outcome> (p = 0.014) <outcome>and greater upset by hair loss</outcome> in NCG (p = 0.01). The available data indicate that wearing compression sleeves neither interfere with the level of PA nor decrease quality of life 1 year after breast cancer surgery. 